ANJALI CHAND CERTIFIED DATA SCIENTIST

+91-9819440751 +91-8104256976 ↑
linkedin.com/in/anjali-chand-217b9989 in
anjalichand7@gmail.com ⋈
Mumbai, MH, 400093 •

SUMMARY

Certified Data Scientist with overall 5 years of work experience in Data-Centric Software Testing roles. Intermediate level of knowledge of analytical stack (Python, SQL, Statistics, Machine Learning Models, and NLP). Experienced in collecting, analyzing, and interpreting large datasets, developing software solutions, and performing data management tasks. Possessing extensive analytical skills, strong attention to detail and a significant ability to work in team environment.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Packages: SciKit Learn, Numpy, SciPy, Plot.py, Pandas, NLTK, Matplotlib, Flask, Seaborn
- Big Data Stack: Python, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Linux, Hadoop
- Statistics/ML/NLP: Linear/Logistic Regression, K-Nearest Neighbors, Random Forest, Naive Bayes, Clustering, BERT, GloVE, CNN, RNN, MobileNetV2
- · Visualization: Tableau, OlikSense

PROJECTS.....

<u>Text Classification for Statements using DistilBERT(Capstone) - NLP</u>

- A binary classifier to identify whether a statement is Judgemental or Non-Judgemental.
- · A data set of 320 sentences is created with balanced classes.
- Final Model used with DistilBERT and Logistic Regression (Tried TF-IDF, Bi-Directional RNN with GloVe)
- Accuracy on Test Data is 75% and on Train Data is 80%.
- Deployed the end model on Heroku using Streamlit

Mango Image Binary Classifier - Deep Learning

- Binary Classifier to identify Alphonso and Non-Alphonso Mangoes seeing at the pictures of mango.
- Web scraped images to get Alphanso and Non-Alphanso Mango Images for Dataset (300 images)
- Trained with CNN and MobileNetV2 pre-trained model.
- · Used image augmentation to train the images and performed hyperparameter tuning
- Accuracy of Model on training set is 79% and on validation set is 82%

<u>Airbnb New User Bookings Prediction : Machine Learning Multi Classification</u>

- Predict which country a new user's first booking destination will be over a data-set of size (Training: 213451, 16)
- Handled multi-collinearity and performed feature engineering
- Performed Bi-Variate and Multi-Variate Analysis on the dataset
- Performed Random Forest with accuracy 0.6248 and Naive Bayes (Bernoulli NB) with accuracy 0.556.

<u>Used Car Price Prediction: Machine Learning Regression</u>

- Prediction of Used car price over a data-set of size (Training: 6019, 13)
- Performed EDA on the data-set and imputed missing values with appropriate measures.
- Performed KNN Regressor and Linear Regression for prediction. KNN R²= 0.8551 and Linear Regression R² = 0.68

WORK EXPERIENCE

INSTITUTIONAL SHAREHOLDER SERVICES / DEC 2020 - PRESENT / SENIOR SOFTWARE TEST ENGINEER

- Verifying that different Analytical Reports that are generated by the DataDesk application have correct data.
- Verifying 3500+ data points (internal + external) of DataDesk application, Database tables, and API responses.
- Works daily on Linux scripting, and SQL Query Execution.
- Developing new test cases for automation test suite of ESG (Environmental, Social and Governance) Services (API Calls)
- API testing of (GET, POST) HTTP requests using PostMan.
- Team Management and assigning tasks to the junior team members.

ZYCUS / FEB 2019 - DEC 2020 / SOFTWARE TEST ENGINEER

- Deployed ZKH (Multi-Nomial Naive-Bayes) model which tags almost 70% Accurate categories for Vendor transactions.
- Developed a Java Application to pull data from MongoDB collection to Excel file
- Developed an application to transfer millions of records from multiple DBs to a single DB table which reduced users efforts by almost 30%
- · Checking the data integrity and consistency after performing required transactions and operations from end to end.
- Collaborate with Functional Team to evaluate or analyze problems and recommend possible solutions.

MAJESCO / NOV 2016 - FEB 2019 / SOFTWARE TEST ENGINEER

- Analyzed possible anomalies in General Ledger accounts of insurance transactions and reported them.
- · Worked closely with data to analyze the flaws in database entries made after performing end-to-end transactions.
- · Worked closely with payment data and identified issues in fees and premium transactions.
- Provide feedback and recommendations to developers on software usability and functionality.

EDUCATION

EXECUTIVE POST GRADUATION PROGRAM / APR 2019 - MAR 2021

GPA

Aegis School Of Business , Data Science & Telecommunication

3.2 / 4.0

GRADUATION (BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING - IT) / SEP 2012 - MAY 2016

Shree L R Tiwari College of Engineering

7.32 / 10.0

AWARDS

- · Awarded twice for on-time and quality delivery (2 spot awards) in Zycus
- Awarded thrice for outstanding performance in consecutive releases (2 Spot Awards and 1 Stellar Award) in Majesco